Samuel George Morton Papers 1819-1850 Mss.B.M843
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 2.25 Linear feet 5 boxes, 486 items.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 8, 1826; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Lyceum of Natural History (New York)
    New York, A.L.S.: Jer. Van Rensselaer, corresponding secy. 1p. and add. Notification of election to membership.
  - Letter to [Samuel George Morton], Feb. 29, 1826; 7 3/4" X 9 3/4"; McClellan, George, 1796-1847
    Harrisburg, [c.]. A.L.S. 2p.
  - Letter to [Samuel George Morton], May 2, 1827; 8" x 10"; Hodgkin, Thomas, 1798-1866
    [London] A.L.S. 4p. Mentions edition of "Dorsey's Surgery." Medical questions. Zoological Society.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 3, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Friendly letter. Scientific news.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 5, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Is applying to vacant chair at University of Baltimore.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 25, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; DeKay, James Ellsworth, 1792-1851
    New York, A.L.S. (?) 2p. and add. Regarding his book on American fossils, and Morton's help with it.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 12, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Bowdoin college, Brunswick, Me., A.L.S. 4p.add. Reagrding new edition of his Mineralogy; seeks Morton's assistance.
  - Letter to S[amuel] George Morton, Sept. 13, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    Steubenville, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Regarding shells, minerals.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 20, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Bowdoin college, Brunswick, Me., A.L.S. 2p. and add. Asks scientific questions, solicits news.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, as secretary of the Academy of natural sciences of Philadelphia, Sept. 24, 1827; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Académie royale des sciences (France)
    Paris, L.S: B.G. Cuvier. 1p. and add. In French. Acknowledges publications sent by the Academy.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 22, 1827; 7 1/4" x 7 1/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Is sending shells.
  - Letter to Samuel Geo[rge] Morton, Oct.12, 1828; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding pamphlet, fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 9, 1828; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Describes recently discovered remnants of whales.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 18, 1828; 8" x 10"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Engraved L.S.: G[eorge] Ord, secretary. 1p. and add. Elected member.
  - Letter to [Thomas] Hodgkin, Feb. 28, 1828; 7 1/4" x 8 3/4"; Sowerby, James de Carle, 1787-1871
    Lambeth, A.L. in 3d P. 3p. and add. Regarding Dr. Morton. Sending specimens.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, March 10, 1828; 7 1/2" x 9"; Doornik, Jacob Elisa, 1777-1837
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and end. In French.
  - Letter to [Samuel George Morton], May 19, 1828; 8" x 10"; Hodgkin, Thomas, 1798-1866
    [London] A.L.S. 4p. Mentions Dr. Sowerby. Regarding specimens. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Samuel] George Morton, June 7, 1828; 8 1/4" x 10"; Bardi, J. comte de
    Florence, A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to [Samuel] George Morton, June 7, 1828; 7 1/2" x 9 3/4"; La Roche, R., (René), 1795-1872
    Florence, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Refers to Count Bardi who wants to enter into correspondence.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 1, 1828; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    Steubenville, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Refers to shells he sent. Solicits shells from Academy.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 26, 1828; 8" x 9 1/2"; Cooper, William
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding his election to Academy of Natural Sciences. Mentions suspensions of Annals of the Lyceum.
  - Letter to [Samuel] George Morton, March 11, 1829; 7 3/4" x 10"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Thanks for journal.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 19, 1829; 5" x 8"; Mitchill, Samuel L., (Samuel Latham), 1764-1831
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Regarding fossils.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 8, 1829; 7 1/4" x 9"; Wright, S.
    Cork, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Sends zoological work.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 10, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hayden, Horace H., 1769-1844
    Bedford Springs, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Regarding pamphlet on fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 13, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; McEuen, Thomas
    Long Branch, A.L.S, 2p. and add. Regarding fossils. Will watch Lukens' dog.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, Sept. 14, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Finch, John
    Hartford, Conn., A.L.S. 1p. and add. (Contains autograph note by Dr. Morton that claims Finch is "entirely wrong".) Refutes Morton's claim that he expressed certain opinion re. fossils.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Sept. 17, 1829; 7 3/4" x 10"; Dexter, Andrew Alfred, 1809-1854
    Summit Bridge, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Reagarding drawings and tables he prepared for Morton.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 19, 1829; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Too late to include communication in next Journal.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 26, 1829; 8" x 10"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Rensselaer School, Troy, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Refers to Rensselaer. Refers to differences in opinion.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 14, 1829; 8" x 9 3/4"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Refers to Mr. Wetherill.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 16, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; DeKay, James Ellsworth, 1792-1851
    A.L.S. (?) 2p. and add. Descriptions and figures in recent publications have been "woefully confused". Regarding fossils. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 24, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Troy, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Responds to essay in Silliman's Journal.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 10, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Introduces his son, a "real botanist". Refers to Silliman.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 18, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding payment for submission.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 30, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Regarding submission of essay.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Dec. 3, 1829; 7 3/4" x 10"; Reynolds, Morris
    London, A.L.S. 4p. add. News of his marriage and new employment. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 17, 1829; 7 1/4" x 9"; Buckland, William, 1784-1856
    Oxford, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Reagrding geology.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 24, 1829; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding essay. Refers to engravings.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 10, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Refers to disagreement with Dr. Chapman (?)
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 22, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Troy, A.L.S. 4p. Referring to insects. On his election to Morton's society.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, March 9, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Too late to insert paper in next issue.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, March 22, 1830; 8" x 9 3/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    Steubenville, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces his son.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, March 29, 1830; 8" x 10"; Atwater, Caleb, 1778-1867
    Circleville, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Regarding specimens. About a letter he wants published.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, April 1, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding paper he submitted.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, April 3, 1830; 7 3/4" x 10 1/4"; Maclure, William, 1763-1840
    Mexico, A.L.S. 4p. add. State of society, barbarity of slavery. Refers to Mr. Owen and New Harmony.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, April 28, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Sending proofs.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 8, 1830; 7 3/4" x 12"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Troy, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Mineralogy. Refers to German naturalist Feuchtwanger.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 12, 1830; 8 1/4" x 10"; Hodgkin, Thomas, 1798-1866
    [London] A.L.S. 4p. add. Friendly letter. Refers to temperance societies.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, May 27, 1830; 8" x 9 3/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    Steubenville, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Regarding the studies of his son.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 29, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Friendly letter. Visit to Philadelphia.
  - Account of some Indian skeletons, May, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Peirson, A. L.
    read before the American academy of arts and sciences, (?). D. 8p.and 1 p1. Freeman Guide 1222. Concerning Indian skeletons found near Col. Peabody's lead factory..
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 31, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning publication.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 17, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Brunswick, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning Bowdoin College. Terms of lectureship.
  - Sam[uel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 11, 1830; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Schweinitz, Lewis David von, 1780-1834
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regardin Dr. Hering's collection.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 10, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Conrad, T. A.
    Charl[e]ston, (?). A.L.S. 1p. and add. Regarding fossils. Refers to Dr. Ravenel.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 20, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; McEuen, Thomas
    Charleston, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Ornithology. Refers to academy.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, March 3, 1831; 8" x 9 3/4"; Wright, S.
    Cork, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Sending a box of shells.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, April 15, 1831; 8" x 9 3/4"; Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. and add. (Contains also a note signed by Jona. Thatcher, April 20,1831). Is sending his Herbarium for the Academy.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, April, 1831; 8" x 10"; Featherstonhaugh, George William, 1780-1866
    [Philadelphia?] A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding the plan for Morton's tabular series.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, June 26, 1831; 7 3/4" x 12 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. add. Sends corrected paper. Regarding his recommendation for a position at the University of Georgia.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, June 30, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding Mr. Shepard's appointment. Mentions University of Georgia position.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 10, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding paper on fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 20, 1831; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Refers to Mr. Mantell.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 20, 1831; 8" x 10"; Brongniart, Alexandre, 1770-1847
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. In French.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 29, 1831; 8" x 12 1/2"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Falmouth, Valparaiso, A.L.S. 4p.add. Is sending bird skins and shells for Academy. Describes log covered in barnacles his ship picked up.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Dec. 6, 1831; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, Sussex, England, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning American fossils. Hopes to communicte more.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, Dec. 9, 1831; 5" x 8"; Harlan, Richard, 1796-1843
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Angry accusation of interference with his patients. Contains an "Apologue" by Dr. Morton.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 12, 1832; 7 1/2" x 9"; Wright, S.
    Cork, A.L.S. 6p. and add. Regarding two skulls he procured. Mentions shells.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 30, 1832; 8" x 13 1/2"; Conrad, T. A.
    near the Santee Canal, (?). A.L.S. 3p. and add. Description of his collecting expedition in the South. Conchology.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, Feb. 8, 1832; 6 1/4" x 7 3/4"; Eaton, Amos, 1776-1842
    Troy, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces Dr. Comstock.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 8, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning essay.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 10, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Quotes from a letter from Dr. Mantell. Refers to Lyell. Regarding fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 20, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning essay. Compliments Morton on accomplishments. Geology.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, March 25, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning paper he printed.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 5, 1832; 8" x 9 1/2"; Cooper, William
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Fossils. Mentions Dr. Pickering. About dividing a collection among various scientists, including Schweinitz, Morton, Lea.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; DeKay, James Ellsworth, 1792-1851
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Compliments Morton's work.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, June 6, 1832; 8" x 9 1/2"; Cooper, William
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning fossils, teeth.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, June 11, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
    Amherst, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Geology of Massachusetts.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, June, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Near Erie, Greene Co., Ala., (?). A.L.S. 2p. and add. (Mutilated). Shells. Includes drawing.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, July 2, 1832; 7 1/4" x 11 3/4"; Cleaveland, Parker, 1780-1858
    Brunswick, (?) A.L.S. 1p. and add. Reagarding recommendation for position at University of Georgia. Mentions his new edition.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, July 2, 1832; 7 1/2" x 8 3/4"; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
    Amherst, A.L.S. 4p. add. Regarding fossils.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, July 18, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9"; Wright, S
    Cork, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Inquirung about box of shells he sent.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, July 24, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for fossils for his Museum. Discusses fossils. Mentions Mr. Lyell.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, July 29, 1832; 8" x 10"; Société française de statistique.
    Paris, L.S.: de Montveran (?) 2p. and add. In French. Regarding membership dues.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 6, 1832; 8" x 9 3/4"; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
    Amherst, A.L.S. 3p. and add. List of specimens. Sending fossils.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 10, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    Valparaiso, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Thanks for election to Academy. Regarding collecting expedition. Ornithology.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Sept. 11, 1832; 8" x 10"; Pitcher, Zina, 1797-1872
    Fort Gibson, A.L.S. 3p. and add. On physiology of Native Americans. Refers to Osage, Algonkin. Discusses fossils. Freeman Guide 2603.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 15, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Tappan, Benjamin, 1773-1857
    Steubenville, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regarding rattlesnakes.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 27, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, Sussex, England, A.L.S. 4P. Is sending specimens. Shells. Mentions "pest" in the city.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 1, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
    Amherst, A.L.S. 3p. and add. (Contains also a note signed: Solo. Pitkin, testifying to shipment of specimens.) Geology. List of specimens.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 5, 1832; 8 1/4" x 10 3/4"; Hodgkin, Thomas, 1798-1866
    London, L.S. 3p. and add. Introduces a patient (a poor man).
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 11, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning Mr. Conrad's new work. Fossils.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 28, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hitchcock, Edward, 1793-1864
    Amherst, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning fossils. Minerals.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 4, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning publications. Mentions Mantell.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Nov. 26, 1832; 8" x 9 1/2"; Cooper, William
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Is sending a unique fossils from Dr. Mather. Refers to American Museum in New York.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 12, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, A.L.S. 4p. Discusses fossil conchology.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l George Morton, Dec. 16, 1832; 8" x 10"; Pitcher, Zina, 1797-1872
    Fort Gibson, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning explorations. Refers to Choctaw emigration. Freeman Guide 742.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Dec. 19, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, Sussex, England, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning fossils.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 21, 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning his journal.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Dec. 27, 1832; 7 1/4" x 9 1/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Smithville, N.C., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Describes his collecting expedition. Difficulties using dredge. Shells and other fossils.
  - Monody on the death of Margaret M. Collins., 1832; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Morton, Samuel George, 1799-1851
    D. 3p. Poem on occasion of her death.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 1, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    New Haven, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Dissection of mummy would be acceptable for journal.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Jan. 5, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Silliman, Benjamin, Sr., 1779-1864
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Is examining sugar refineries in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Feb. 10, 1833; 8" x 12 3/4"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, Sussex, England, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning shipment of specimens he received. Fossils. Geological publications.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, Feb. 12, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S.2p. and add. Anatomical objects. Shells. Freeman Guide 1296.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Feb. 13, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 1/2"; Ravenel, Edmund, 1797-1871
    Charleston, A.L.S. 2p. add. Mentions Dr. Conrad. Concerning fossils, geology.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, March 3, 1833; 8" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 4p. add. Concerning geology of Southern regions, esp. Georgia.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] Geo[rge] Morton, March 3, 1833; 8"x 12 1/2"; Ruschenberger, W. S. W., (William Samuel Waithman), 1807-1895
    U.S.S. Falmouth, Callao Roads, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning his expedition to South America. Describes birds and shells. Sends collections.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, March 5, 1833; 8" x 10"; Say, Thomas, 1787-1834
    New Harmony, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning fossil shells. Refers to publication of his work.
  - Letter to Sam[uel] G[eorge] Morton, March 12, 1833; 8" x 10"; Société géologique de France
    Paris, Printed L.S: J. Desnoyers, secretary. 3p. and add. In French.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, March, 1833; 7 3/4 " x 9 3/4"; Bird, Robert Montgomery, 1806-1854
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Is leaving on a journey. Does not have time to finish sketch. FILM 403 FRAME 66
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, April 3, 1833; 7 3/4" x 13"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 4p. add. Concerning his collecting expedition in the South. Includes list of specimens. Describes land and people.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, April 20, 1833; 7 3/4" x 13"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, [and] Mobile, April 23, 1833. A.L.S. 3p. and add. (colored drawing of flower). Geology, fossils. Incudes poems.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 8, 1833; 8" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Mobile, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Collecting shells near Mobile, Alabama.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, May 20, 1833; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, England, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Is sending specimens.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, June 4, 1833; 7 1/4" x 9"; Mantell, Gideon Algernon, 1790-1852
    Castle Place, Lewes, A.L. 3p. and add. (Signature has been cut out). Is sending essay on geology.
  - Letter to Samuel George Morton, June 20, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Hildreth, Samuel P. (Samuel Prescott), 1783-1863
    Marietta, O., A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning Crania. Freeman Guide 1297.
  - Letter to [Samuel George] Morton, July 3, 1833; 7 1/4" x 9"; Fitton, William Henry, 1780-1861
    [London], A.L.in 3d P. 2p. and end. Thanks for the papers; is sending some geological papers himself.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, July 21, 1833; 8" x 10"; Cramer, Charles
    St. Petersburg, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Thanks for donation to Mineralogical Society. Refers to Indian skulls, possibly from New Zealand.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l G[eorge] Morton, Aug. 22, 1833; 7 3/4" x 13"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 4p. add. (mutilated). Geology. Describes his Southern expedition. Includes drawing of a shell.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 11, 1833; 7 3/4" x 13"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning his collecting expedition. Mentions Judge Tait.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Sept. 25, 1833; 8" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Concerning his collecting expedition. Fishes, fossils, shells.
  - Letter to D[aniel] Drake, Sept. 28, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Wood, William
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Aboriginal mounds, including bones. Freeman Guide 1243. (On same sheet with letter from Dr. Drake to S.G. Morton, Oct. 29, 1833; Freeman Guide 1208).
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 10, 1833; 8" x 10"; Albany Institute
    Printed L.S: Horace B. Webster. 1p. and add. Elected to membership.
  - Letter to S[amuel] G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 26, 1833; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; Conrad, T. A.
    Claiborne, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerning his collecting expedition. Includes drawings of shells. Geology, fossils.
  - Letter to Samuel G[eorge] Morton, Oct. 28, 1833; 8" x 10"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844